newsweaver.co.uk 2013-11-06

# Privacy Policy | Software that Drives Engagement

We take the privacy of visitors to our website seriously and have set out in this policy documenting how we collect, use and disclose personally identifiable information provided via this website. By visiting the Newsweaver [email marketing](http://www.newsweaver.com/ "email marketing") website, or signing up to email newsletters created and sent through the Newsweaver technology, you are accepting the terms of this privacy policy, so we encourage you to read this entire privacy policy before using or submitting information to this site.

### **Contents**

  * Cookies and other tracking technologies
  * Data collection
  * Data storage, sharing & security
  * Personal data access
  * Business sale or bankruptcy
  * Changes to this privacy policy
  * Contact details

### **Cookies and other tracking technologies**

This is brief explanation of cookies and other tracking technologies. Cookies are small, usually randomly encoded, text files that help you navigate through a website. They are generated on the sites that you visit as well as by third-parties that websites work with to manage key elements of their business user functionality. In most cases they do not involve or use personal information in any way.

They are used extensively online and have become part of the fabric and make-up of what has made the internet work so effectively for consumers and businesses. Without cookies many areas of functionality for example, user logins, shopping baskets and other customisation features will not work.

There are other tracking technologies used with email marketing. Examples include:

  * Flash Locally Stored Objects (eg ‘Flash’ cookies) – these follow the same principle as normal standard cookies in the respect that they allow information to be stored on a user’s machine.
  * Transparent GIF or web beacons- these mechanisms can be used to deliver a cookie to your browser. They can also be used in email marketing to identify to the sender if an email has been opened.

For further information about cookies, you can also visit www.allaboutcookies.org

### **Data collection**

**Browse the Website**

As an anonymous visitor to our website we collect no personally identifiable information about you. We use temporary third party Google Analytics cookies to collect an anonymous record of your site page views and to recognise return visits (also anonymously) using a unique cookie that Google Analytics stores in your browser.  

We use the collected page view information to understand how visitors use the website and to help us improve access to its information and functionality.

**Submitted website requests for example, Book a live demo and Contact us Forms**

If you submit your details on the request a free trial, demo booking form, our contact us form or any other similar form we may implement in the future, we will save your personal details in our CRM (customer relationship management) database.

We also record with temporary third party Google Analytics cookies to provide a best estimate of where you came from before you visited the Newsweaver website e.g. a Google advertisement, Adcampaign, a search listing, or an external link to our site.

When you register for a Free Trial we ask you to choose a password and we then record an encrypted copy of this. We do not know your password, and it is entirely your responsibility to keep it secret and ensure that your account is accessed only by authorized individuals.

This information will be stored in our CRM system and used by our sales or support people to make contact regarding your request for a demo, or other inquiry. We may use your information to contact you again in the future, if we believe we have an offer that may be relevant to you. We may also analyse collected contact information in aggregate form to better inform our future marketing efforts. We record your origin to allow us analyse the effectiveness of our marketing and search engine optimisation efforts.

We also record our best estimate of where you came from before you visited the Newsweaver website for marketing purpose e.g. a Google advertisement, a search listing or an external link to our site.

Our Sales or CRM people will use your contact details to get in touch with you to discuss your email marketing or publishing requirements, and to ensure that you get full benefit from a system trial. We may use your information to contact you again in the future, if we believe that we have an offer that may be relevant to you. We may also analyse collected contact information in aggregate form to better inform our future marketing efforts. We record your origin to allow us analyse the effectiveness of our marketing and search engine optimisation efforts.

**Subscribe to newsletters and flyers such as Business of Email**

When you subscribe to our email newsletter, the Business of Email, we record and save your email address, whether you are a customer or prospect and your format preference. This data is used only to enable us to send you a bimonthly issue of the newsletter in your preferred format.

Newsweaver tracks email opens using an invisible 1×1 pixel unique image that is placed in each email sent by our system i.e. not a cookie.  We use temporary session cookies in microsites, which are necessary for the operation of the system.

If you receive the HTML formatted version of the newsletter and your email client is configured to download images, we will be notified each time you open the email, and this information will be saved with your subscriber record. We also record your clicks on links in the newsletter and in the companion website with your subscriber record.

Issues of the newsletter may carry a survey. If you respond to a survey, your answers are saved with your subscriber record and are used to prevent multiple entries by any individual.

We use the stored open, click and survey information in aggregated form to give us an indication of the popularity of the content and to help us make decisions about future content and formatting. We may also use the information to publish more relevant content to individual newsletter readers in future issues.

You may stop receiving our newsletters at any time by using the Unsubscribe link included in every issue sent. Your email address is retained to ensure you no longer receive communications, unless you choose to re-subscribe.

**Commenting on our blog**

When you comment on our blog, cookies are used so that you won’t need to retype all your information again when you want to leave another comment.

### **Use of the Newsweaver System**

When you begin to use a trial account, you may upload data to the Newsweaver application in the form of subscriber lists and newsletter content to be published to your subscribers. All this data remains entirely yours and is only stored and processed by Newsweaver for the purposes of providing a newsletter publishing service to you. Note that the data lists and content you upload are subject to our Anti-spam and Terms of Use policies respectively.

If you wish to become a paying client of Newsweaver, we will request sufficient additional contact and other information such as billing details from you to allow us provide a contract-based service to you. This information will be used solely to enable the provision of our email newsletter publishing service to you.

When you use the Newsweaver system, we record a log of all significant actions taken by you while logged in, together with related information such as browser and OS type, and IP address. We use this information to estimate system load, and to plan for system expansion and browser support. The information would also be used to allow us investigate incidents such as those involving compromised login credentials.

### **Data Storage, Sharing & Security**

Customer data in the form of subscriber lists and newsletter content, and other application data relating to the newsletter publishing service, are securely stored in our application servers and will never be shared with third parties, except where we are required to do so by law.

We employ industry-accepted levels of security on all data storage and transmission.

Your contact, billing and other details will never be shared or stored with third parties, except where we are legally obliged to do so, or where we make use of an external service to operate some aspect of our business, such as credit card processing, or CRM. In such instances, the storage of your data on third party systems will be solely for the purpose of operating our business to provide you with the contracted service, and never for the direct benefit of the third party, who will never have any other right of use to your data.

Where we make use of an external service in this way, we will require the same commitment to the security of your data as we ourselves implement.

We retain personal data only as long as required to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected as outlined in this policy, or as long as we are legally obliged to do so.

### **Personal Data Access**

You may request a copy of any personal data we hold about you by using the contact details at the end of this policy. You may request that any incorrect data be amended, or alter your communications preferences at any time.

### **Business Sale or Bankruptcy**

Your contact data is an asset of our business. If Newsweaver were to be acquired, or in the unlikely event of its going out of business, ownership of your data would transfer to a third party. Your data would remain subject to the terms as set out in our privacy policy at the time of the transaction, until such time as you were notified of any change by the new owner. Your rights to access or to have your data corrected would be unaffected.

**Data Protection**

Newsweaver is registered with the Information Commissioner’s Office in the UK and the Data Protection Commissioner in Ireland.

### **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to make changes to this privacy policy. Changes will be posted on this website thirty days prior to such changes becoming effective. Where we propose to make changes to how we collect, use or disclose personal data that could reduce the privacy of its owner in any way, we will notify by email all persons potentially affected, with an opportunity to opt out of such use.

### **Contact Details**

If you have any queries about this privacy policy, please contact us at [privacy@newsweaver.com](mailto:privacy@newsweaver.com)

or write to:  
Data Protection Officer  
Newsweaver  
2200 Airport Business Park  
Cork  
Ireland  
Tel: +353-21-242-7277  
Fax: +353-21-458-0462

Effective date: May/2012
